<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Events on Anand Chowdhary</title>
    <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Events on Anand Chowdhary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 10:26:42 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://anandchowdhary.com/events/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AKEPT-WIEF Social Enterprise Forum</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/wief-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 29 Mar 2018 10:26:42 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/wief-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll be speaking about social entrepreneurship at the AKEPT-WIEF Social Enterprise Forum in Kuala Lumpur later this year. The event is a collaboration between the higher education and leadership academy AKEPT and the World Islamic Economic Forum Foundation.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NESST</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/nesst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/nesst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After being featured by Het Financieele Dagblad (Dutch Financial Times) as one of the Netherlands&amp;rsquo; 50 most-innovative young entrepreneurs and professionals, I was invited by Enschede-based non-profit startup accelerator NESST to deliver the opening keynote for their new season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup24</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/startup24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/startup24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Startup24 is the flagship startup weekend-like event in the Netherlands which happens in 12 cities simultaneously. I was invited to Startup24 Enschede to do a pitching working for the participants before their final jury pitches, and I was also part of their &amp;ldquo;midnight jury&amp;rdquo; for 2-minute pitches at midnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardstart Pitch Training</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/hardstart-pitch-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/hardstart-pitch-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I developed and conducted a startup pitching workshop for student entrepreneurship organization and incubator Hardstart&amp;rsquo;s flagship pitching event, &lt;em&gt;Pitch that Bitch&lt;/em&gt;. It was the first time that I conducted a workshop for fellow student entrepreneurs, and it was definitely a very interesting experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BharatHacks</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/bharathacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/bharathacks/</guid>
      <description>I organized BharatHacks, a hackathon for solving India-specific problems. Programmers, designers, engineers, and entrepreneurs came together to build products to make the lives of a billion Indians better. I organized in collaboration with Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Developer Circle Delhi-NCR and delivered the introductory keynote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEDxHaileyRoad</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/tedx-hailey-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/tedx-hailey-road/</guid>
      <description>I gave my first TEDx talk at TEDxHaileyRoad in New Delhi in June 2017 on Designing for Inclusion, where I talked about my story in starting Oswald Labs and rethinking today&amp;rsquo;s approach to ignore accessibility and inclusion in design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Charcha by Facebook DevC</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/tech-charcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/tech-charcha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was part of a panel discussion on the future of technology by Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Developer Circles Delhi-NCR along with Chinmaya Saxena, Developer Programs Lead, Facebook India; Saransh Kataria, Chapter Lead, Facebook Developer Circle Delhi; and Shubhamoy Chakrabarty, COO at Cloudtub, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIP Launch (DTU)</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/sip-launch-dtu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/sip-launch-dtu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was the keynote speaker at the launch of the Startup Internship Portal of Delhi Technological University (DTU), where I did the first public revealing of Oswald Labs&amp;rsquo; R&amp;amp;D blind-friendly smartphone OS, Shravan and talked about the opportunity of working with startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>coDelhi</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/codelhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/codelhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spoke about education technology and my startup ClassRebels at Co|Delhi, the flagship Android and web development hackathon of Delhi Technological University (DTU). I delivered two talks, one on the first day about edtech and the other about our stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>