<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Open-source on Anand Chowdhary</title>
    <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Open-source on Anand Chowdhary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Uppload</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/uppload/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 19 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/uppload/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Uppload is an open-source JavaScript file uploader. It has built-in support for drag-and-dropping, image cropping, file previews,  Instagram imports, and more. It works with any HTML form backend and has wrappers for Vue.js, React, and Angular, and presets for Firebase and AWS S3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Precis</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/precis/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 Dec 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/precis/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Precis is a free and open-source URL shortener which uses PHP and MySQL. It has an admin panel with a RESTful API and collects analytics such as useragent with each click. It works across multiple domains and is super easy to setup.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Grid</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/one-grid/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/one-grid/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;One Grid is the simplest grid system for fixed-height infinite blocks in less than one kilobyte. It&amp;rsquo;s responsive, eliminates unnecessary code, and works with Internet Explorer 8+. One is the most fundamental form of what I believe a grid system should work like.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Aptitude</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/aptitude/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/aptitude/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Aptitude is a super-simple theme for one-page articles and projects. It&amp;rsquo;s the next version of essential.css and comes with support for better navigation, icons, and fonts from Typekit. It was created for a page on my website, &lt;a href=&#34;https://anandchowdhary.com/timeless/&#34;&gt;Timeless&lt;/a&gt;, something I maintain until today.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>essential.css</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/essential.css/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/essential.css/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;essential.css is a beautiful article template in 786 bytes. Just include the stylesheet link to your webpage and quickly create simple, readable webpages. I made essential.css as a tool to build my personal website and open-sourced it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ac.js</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/ac.js/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Oct 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/open-source/ac.js/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the end of 2012, with increasing support for new JavaScript APIs, I created a super-tiny library for fetching and manipulating DOM elements. The first version was just 696 bytes in size, and the updated second version was 231 bytes gzipped. This was the first public-use JavaScript library I made (honestly, it was barely a library).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>