<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Anand Chowdhary</title>
	<atom:link href="/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/</link>
	<description></description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 28 Dec 2017 18:11:34 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>hourly</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>1</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=4.9.2</generator>
	<item>
		<title>FaceMatch</title>
		<link>/facematch/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 26 Sep 2017 12:20:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Projects]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[App]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Face Detection]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hackathon]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Machine Learning]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Mobile]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=313</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[For the Amazon Web Services (AWS) Hackathon at The Future of High Tech, part of the Startup Fest Europe 2017, I developed FaceMatch, a mobile app that uses deep learning-based facial detection, and displays the results in an augmented reality heads-up display. I ended up winning the hackathon’s grand prize of €1,000 along with VIP tickets for StartupFest Europe.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>For the Amazon Web Services (AWS) Hackathon at <a href="http://www.thefutureofhightech.com/">The Future of High Tech</a>, part of the Startup Fest Europe 2017, I developed FaceMatch, a mobile app that uses deep learning-based facial detection, and displays the results in an augmented reality heads-up display. I ended up winning the hackathon&#8217;s grand prize of €1,000 along with VIP tickets for StartupFest Europe.</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/FB_IMG_1506591590350-1.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-314" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/FB_IMG_1506591590350-1.jpg" alt="" width="1225" height="817" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/FB_IMG_1506591590350-1.jpg 1225w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/FB_IMG_1506591590350-1-300x200.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/FB_IMG_1506591590350-1-768x512.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/FB_IMG_1506591590350-1-1024x683.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1225px) 100vw, 1225px" /></a></p>
<p>The idea is simple — if you enter a large conference or a room full of people, you want to know who you should network with. FaceMatch uses AI to understand faces, and finds their relevant info from their LinkedIn profiles. This means that you can essentially point the phone at someone, get information like their age, gender, expression, designation, and company, along with a link to their LinkedIn profile.</p>
<p>I also added a second feature for users who are visually impaired or blind. FaceMatch View reads out the information of the people it recognizes, so if you’re partially or completely blind, you can understand who’s around. “Anand Chowdhary is in the frame, and he’s 19 years old, CEO/Product at Oswald Foundation” will be read out, as an example.</p>
<p>It also uses object and scene detection, so you can just point your camera in the direction you’re walking in, and it will tell you what’s around. “In this scene, there is: road, lamppost, footpath, grass, tree” will be read out to you. For reading out, I used <em>ResponsiveVoice</em>, an instant text-to-speech and speech synthesis library that ensures voice consistency across platforms.</p>
<p>FaceMatch uses Amazon Rekognition, a service that lets you quickly add sophisticated deep learning-based visual search and image classification to apps. I ended up using Face Comparison, Facial Analysis, and Object and Scene Detection APIs.</p>
<p>PS: I ended up winning the grand prize of €1,000, along with VIP tickets to the Startup Fest Europe in Amsterdam!</p>
<p>The code is available on <a href="https://github.com/AnandChowdhary/facematch">GitHub</a>. Here are some slides:</p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0001.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-319" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0001.jpg" alt="" width="4267" height="3200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0001.jpg 4267w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0001-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0001-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0001-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4267px) 100vw, 4267px" /></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0002.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-320" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0002.jpg" alt="" width="4267" height="3200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0002.jpg 4267w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0002-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0002-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0002-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4267px) 100vw, 4267px" /></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0003.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-321" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0003.jpg" alt="" width="4267" height="3200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0003.jpg 4267w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0003-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0003-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0003-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4267px) 100vw, 4267px" /></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0004.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-322" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0004.jpg" alt="" width="4267" height="3200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0004.jpg 4267w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0004-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0004-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0004-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4267px) 100vw, 4267px" /></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0006.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-324" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0006.jpg" alt="" width="4267" height="3200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0006.jpg 4267w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0006-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0006-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0006-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4267px) 100vw, 4267px" /></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0007.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-325" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0007.jpg" alt="" width="4267" height="3200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0007.jpg 4267w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0007-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0007-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0007-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4267px) 100vw, 4267px" /></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0008.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-326" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0008.jpg" alt="" width="4267" height="3200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0008.jpg 4267w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0008-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0008-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0008-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4267px) 100vw, 4267px" /></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0010.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-328" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0010.jpg" alt="" width="4267" height="3200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0010.jpg 4267w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0010-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0010-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0010-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4267px) 100vw, 4267px" /></a></p>
<p><a href="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0011.jpg"><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-329" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0011.jpg" alt="" width="4267" height="3200" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0011.jpg 4267w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0011-300x225.jpg 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0011-768x576.jpg 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/10/0011-1024x768.jpg 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 4267px) 100vw, 4267px" /></a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Hacking UTwente&#8217;s PeoplePages</title>
		<link>/hacking-utwentes-peoplepages/</link>
		<pubDate>Sat, 12 Aug 2017 13:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coffee Time]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Code]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hacking]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSON]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=289</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[As a future CreaTe student at the University of Twente, I wanted to get in touch with a particular professor. Their website, PeoplePages, uses a RESTful API for AJAX requests to search for university staff, so I decided to add everyone to my contacts. (Also makes sending LinkedIn requests to everyone much easier.) See how I did it and how they could improve their security, so others can't.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>As a future CreaTe student at the University of Twente, I wanted to get in touch with a particular professor. Their website, <a href="https://people.utwente.nl/">PeoplePages</a>, uses a RESTful API for AJAX requests to search for university staff, so I decided to add everyone to my contacts. (Also makes sending LinkedIn requests to everyone much easier.)</p>
<p>I did a query to find all results starting with the letter &#8220;a&#8221; and got a minified JSON response with all data. Fortunately, they have unrestricted access to their endpoints. This is what it looks like when cleaned:</p>
<pre>GET https://people.utwente.nl/search?query=a</pre>
<pre>{
	"data":[
		{
			"type":"person",
			"id":"10000000000XXXX",
			"name":"John Doe",
			"jobtitle":"Supporting Staff",
			"avatar":"https://people.utwente.nl/john.doe/picture.jpg",
			"profile":"https://people.utwente.nl/john.doe",
			"organizations":[
				{
					"code":"S&amp;B-XXXX",
					"department":"S&amp;B",
					"section":"XXXX"
				}
			],
			"locations":[
				{
					"description":"Enschede 320",
					"latitude":52.23979,
					"longitude":6.850018
				}
			],
			"phones":[
				{
					"type":"",
					"tel":"+3153489XXXX",
					"prefix":"+3153489",
					"ext":"XXXX"
				}
			],
			"email":"john.doe@utwente.nl"
		}
	]
}</pre>
<p>and so on. Since empty searches, space searches, and others weren&#8217;t working, I decided to query each letter of the alphabet and save the JSON result to play with it:</p>
<pre>wget https://people.utwente.nl/search?query={a..z}</pre>
<p>I soon realized that this wouldn&#8217;t work because the API restricts the number of results to 50, but this would:</p>
<pre>wget https://people.utwente.nl/search?query={a..z}{a..z}</pre>
<p>This goes through every combination in the alphabet: aa, ab, ac . . . zx, zy, zz, and downloads the JSON file. This was enough, but in many combinations, there were no results, so the empty JSON file was exactly 43 bytes. I then got rid of those files:</p>
<pre>find . -name "*" -size 43c -delete</pre>
<p>This Bash command finds all files that are of 43 bytes in size and deletes them. Note that if I just filter the size in bytes and query something like <code>-size 43 -delete</code>, it <a href="https://superuser.com/a/644274">interprets it as</a> 43*512 bytes, so the POSIX requirement states &#8220;c&#8221; for bytes.</p>
<p>Finally I concatenated all the JSON files to one giant 4.9 MB file.</p>
<pre class="p1"><span class="s1">cat * &gt; contacts.json</span></pre>
<p>After cleaning the file, removing business contacts, and generally playing with the JSON content, I have a directory of 7527 people including duplicates. Sublime Text can handle this for me, with the simple command: Edit -&gt; Permute Lines -&gt; Unique. I now have 3740 people.</p>
<p>Then, I clean up by replacing double space with single, change the &#8220;Surname, Firstname&#8221; format to &#8220;Firstname Surname&#8221;, and saved the contacts in a CSV file.</p>
<p>Simple enough, but I now have the phone numbers, email addresses, and office addresses of all my professors, the Dean, and other important contacts for the university. Simple enough.</p>
<h3>Security</h3>
<p>The simple way to prevent this is to have secured API endpoints. There are many ways to do that &#8212; token-based authentication for each user with rate limiting, or even CORS prevention.</p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-304" src="https://www.accessibility.technology/websites/anand/anandchowdhary.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Screen-Shot-2017-08-12-at-6.32.24-PM.png" alt="" width="1273" height="833" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Screen-Shot-2017-08-12-at-6.32.24-PM.png 1273w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Screen-Shot-2017-08-12-at-6.32.24-PM-300x196.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Screen-Shot-2017-08-12-at-6.32.24-PM-768x503.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/08/Screen-Shot-2017-08-12-at-6.32.24-PM-1024x670.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1273px) 100vw, 1273px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>University of Twente</title>
		<link>/twente/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 12 Jun 2017 02:10:34 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=146</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[In my post <a href="/college/">Life Update: College</a>, I said that Creative Technology at the University of Twente was my absolute favorite program after researching through tens of leading universities and their design and engineering programs. I'm super excited to announce that that's what I'll be studying this year.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>In my post <a href="/college/">Life Update: College</a>, I said that Creative Technology at the University of Twente was my absolute favorite program after researching through tens of leading universities and their design and engineering programs. I&#8217;m super excited to announce that that&#8217;s what I&#8217;ll be studying this year.</p>
<p>The UT has a beautiful 1.5 km<sup>2</sup> campus in Enschede. Enschede is the 13th largest city in the Netherlands, with a population about 158,000. It has a <a href="https://commons.wikimedia.org/wiki/File:Flag_of_Enschede.svg">beautiful city flag</a> and is an incredibly entrepreneurial city, with the Novel-T Accelerator, Kennispark Business Center, and over 400 startups. I&#8217;ll be living in the Mondriaan, named after the Dutch painter, on the Calslaan.</p>
<p>I&#8217;m especially passionate about the Creative Technology program (CreaTe) based it&#8217;s a perfect marriage of design and technology. The first year consists of four modules &#8212; We Create Identity, Smart Environments, <span style="font-weight: 400;">Living and working Tomorrow, and Art, Impact and Technology.</span></p>
<p>We Create Identity is essentially introductory, consisting of programming, introduction to computer science and engineering, a week of math, visual communication design, web tech, video, and more. I personally love the diverse nature of the program, since I&#8217;m super interested in both engineering and design. All modules end with a project/portfolio item, alongside an essay or reflection.</p>
<p>The second module has a pretty descriptive name, Smart Environments. It&#8217;s got everything from sketching, project management, and time management, to the hardcore physical computing and programming lectures. Mathematics and modelling and systematic engineering and design are two classes I&#8217;m particularly interested in. I don&#8217;t have any prior hardware/electronics knowledge, so this is something I&#8217;m extremely looking forward to.</p>
<p>Living and working Tomorrow, Ideation and Explorative Design is essentially the natural step after Smart Environments and deals with the intrinsic designs of these devices. Interactive visualization and rapid prototyping, <span style="font-weight: 400;">physical and dynamical systems, contextual design, etc. Art, Impact and Technology is the final module that consists of algorithms, statistics, human factors, and pitching.</span></p>
<p>What&#8217;s exciting me is that all of this is just the first year of CreaTe. I also gave an interview to <a href="http://bwdisrupt.businessworld.in/article/Oswald-Foundation-10-Month-Old-Startup-Goes-Multinational/14-07-2017-122124/">BW Disrupt</a> about opening an office for Oswald Foundation in Enschede. I hope to take some of our technology to the European markets, and I&#8217;m super excited about the doors Twente will open for me.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BharatHacks</title>
		<link>/bharathacks/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 10 May 2017 03:25:21 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Projects]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=178</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[This June, I'm organizing BharatHacks, a hackathon for solving India-specific problems. Programmers, designers, engineers, and entrepreneurs will come together to build products to make lives better. Organizated in collaboration with Facebook Developer Circle Delhi-NCR, BharatHacks will help you take your idea forward, from hacking to raising investment and launching your product in the market.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>This June, I&#8217;m organizing BharatHacks, a hackathon for solving India-specific problems. Programmers, designers, engineers, and entrepreneurs will come together to build products to make lives better. Organized in collaboration with <a href="https://www.facebook.com/groups/DevCDelhiNCR/" target="_blank" rel="noopener noreferrer">Facebook Developer Circle Delhi-NCR</a>, BharatHacks will help you take your idea forward, from hacking to raising investment and launching your product in the market.</p>
<p>BharatHacks is free for both entrepreneurs and hackers, to join hands and work towards a better India. From a pool of over 1,000 applicants, we’ve chosen the top 200 to participate at BharatHacks.</p>
<p>Participants have an opportunity to pitch their ideas to industry-leading investors and startup mentors, including Anil Chhikara, ex-Principal of Jaarvis Accelerator; Bharat Sethi, Forbes 30 Under 30; Paritosh Sharma, Author; and many more. There are prizes worth thousands of dollars.</p>
<p>I&#8217;ve partnered with some incredible technology companies to make BharatHacks a possibility, including DigitalOcean, which is offering free servers to all participants, the .tech registry that’s providing free domain names to all participants, and IBM’s Global Entrepreneur Program, iSPIRT, the parent organization of IndiaStack (the team behind Aadhaar, UPI, and eKYC APIs). Other partners include Neuron, Digio, HackerEarth, Aadhaar Bridge, .tech, F6S, HackSociety, Melangebox, Bizztor, and more.</p>
<p><a href="https://bharathacks.com/">Visit the website →</a></p>
<p><a href="https://bizztor.com/bharathacks/">View the Press Release →</a></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-191" src="https://www.accessibility.technology/websites/anand/anandchowdhary.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.13-AM.png" alt="" width="1309" height="799" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.13-AM.png 1309w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.13-AM-300x183.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.13-AM-768x469.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.13-AM-1024x625.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1309px) 100vw, 1309px" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-190" src="https://www.accessibility.technology/websites/anand/anandchowdhary.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.21-AM.png" alt="" width="1309" height="799" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.21-AM.png 1309w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.21-AM-300x183.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.21-AM-768x469.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.21-AM-1024x625.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1309px) 100vw, 1309px" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-189" src="https://www.accessibility.technology/websites/anand/anandchowdhary.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.33-AM.png" alt="" width="1309" height="799" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.33-AM.png 1309w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.33-AM-300x183.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.33-AM-768x469.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.33-AM-1024x625.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1309px) 100vw, 1309px" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-188" src="https://www.accessibility.technology/websites/anand/anandchowdhary.com/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.37-AM.png" alt="" width="1309" height="799" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.37-AM.png 1309w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.37-AM-300x183.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.37-AM-768x469.png 768w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/06/Screen-Shot-2017-06-12-at-11.40.37-AM-1024x625.png 1024w" sizes="(max-width: 1309px) 100vw, 1309px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Zomato for Android Redesign</title>
		<link>/zomato/</link>
		<pubDate>Tue, 11 Apr 2017 03:07:05 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">/?p=111</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I took fifteen minutes to make some strategic design changes to Zomato's Android app. I wrote extensively about the iconography, typography, and role of actions in the app's user experience. I wrote this article originally in March 2016 for the Zomato Android team and publically published it in April 2017 since Zomato decided to implement most of my design changes.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I took fifteen minutes to make some strategic design changes to Zomato&#8217;s Android app. I wrote extensively about the iconography, typography, and role of actions in the app&#8217;s user experience. I wrote this article originally in March 2016 for the Zomato Android team and publically published it in April 2017 since Zomato decided to implement most of my design changes.</p>
<p><a href="https://medium.com/@anandchowdhary/zomato-for-android-redesign-6ced8b220544">Read the article on Medium →</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Life Update: College</title>
		<link>/college/</link>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Mar 2017 09:10:17 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coffee Time]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://accessibility.co.in/websites/anandchowdhary.com/?p=61</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Just a little bit of background about my college "situation": I graduated from highschool in April 2016 and joined the Unitedworld Institute of Design (UID) in Ahmedabad, Gujarat, after working at the Government of Delhi for a month. UID was an excellent college for people who want to study design using the fundamentals of art. I'll push in an update if I decide to join a program.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Just a little bit of background about my college &#8220;situation&#8221;: I graduated from highschool in April 2016 and joined the Unitedworld Institute of Design (UID) in Ahmedabad, Gujarat, after working at the Government of Delhi for a month. UID was an excellent college for people who want to study design using the fundamentals of art.</p>
<p>The problem I faced at UID was that the first year, the Foundation, was really more art and design. Instead of design thinking and languages and designers, it was more about sketching and painting and artists. The way I think design should be taught, really what I feel design is, was very different from their philosophy. So, after two short months, I decided to drop out of UID. I moved back to Delhi and founded Oswald Foundation, the accessibility technology company I&#8217;m leading.</p>
<p>Oswald went on to become really great, and it mainly started with us winning Startup India Rocks! 2016 and I decided that it&#8217;s worthwhile. This January, I applied to a few universities I liked just to keep my options open, in case I wish to continue my formal education. Even though Oswald is going great, I figured it&#8217;s no harm in applying.</p>
<h3>Accepted</h3>
<ol>
<li>Digital Media at RMIT University</li>
<li>Digital Media &amp; Visual Communication at HTK Berlin</li>
<li>Interaction Design at Harbour.Space University (1 year scholarship)</li>
<li>Interaction Design at The Glasgow School of Art</li>
<li><span data-sheets-value="{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:&quot;Information Technology&quot;}" data-sheets-userformat="{&quot;2&quot;:2561,&quot;3&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:0},&quot;12&quot;:0,&quot;14&quot;:{&quot;1&quot;:2,&quot;2&quot;:0}}">Information Technology with UX at University of Queensland</span></li>
<li>Digital Media Design at University of Hertfordshire</li>
<li>Applied Computer Science (Mobile Computing) at Sheridan College</li>
<li>Interaction Design Arts at University of the Arts London&#8217;s College of Communication</li>
<li>Interaction Design at California College of the Arts (Creative Achievement scholarship, $80,000)</li>
<li>Interaction Design at Norwich University of the Arts</li>
<li>Creative Technology at the University of Twente</li>
</ol>
<h3>Rejected</h3>
<ol>
<li>Digital and Interaction Design at BTK University, Berlin, because I needed a foundation year to apply for that program. I did not know that.</li>
</ol>
<h3>Footnotes</h3>
<p>University of Twente&#8217;s Creative Technology program is my absolute favorite right now. If I have to choose a course, I would pick this program because it&#8217;s the perfect blend of creativity/design, engineering, and computer science &#8212; everything I love.</p>
<p>I did not apply to study to the US, except for CCA because it’s been my dream college since I was in sixth grade. I really loved the Interaction Design program at CCA when I was younger, but I see the parallels between UID and CCA in retrospect.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Defence for MD5</title>
		<link>/md5/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 26 Feb 2017 09:07:20 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coffee Time]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://accessibility.co.in/websites/anandchowdhary.com/?p=57</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[A few days ago, I tried to reset my password on PR.com, the press releases website. I entered my email, and they sent me the username and password in plain text. That’s right, in plain text.

The problem with this method of password storage is that if anyone gets access to your database, they can literally just see the passwords. This is why hashing is used, which converts the plain text password to an encrypted “hashed” version that is, in an ideal world, undecryptable. The problem with this hashing is really about how hashing fundamentally works: collisions are not uncommon, i.e., multiple strings could have the same hashed string.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>A few days ago, I tried to reset my password on PR.com, the press releases website. I entered my email, and they sent me the username and password in plain text. That’s right, in plain text.</p>
<figure id="attachment_52" style="max-width: 1052px" class="wp-caption alignnone"><img class="wp-image-52 size-full" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/Screen-Shot-2017-04-02-at-8.05.54-PM.png" width="1052" height="724" /><figcaption class="wp-caption-text">&#8220;For your security&#8221;</figcaption></figure>
<p>The problem with this method of password storage is that if anyone gets access to your database, they can literally just see the passwords. This is why hashing is used, which converts the plain text password to an encrypted “hashed” version that is, in an ideal world, undecryptable. The problem with this hashing is really about how hashing fundamentally works: collisions are not uncommon, i.e., multiple strings could have the same hashed string.</p>
<p>For example, if the hash function converts all vowels to “X”, then the hash of “Hello” is “HXllX” and the hash of “Hille” is also “HXIIX”, even though the original strings are definitely distinct. Of course, real world hashing functions are mathematically complex, but collisions are still not that uncommon. This is why the MD5 and <a href="https://security.googleblog.com/2017/02/announcing-first-sha1-collision.html">more recently</a> SHA-1 hashing algorithms aren’t recommended for security usages, and larger ones such as SHA-256 which don&#8217;t have any proven collisions so far are.</p>
<p>These two strings have the same MD5 hash:</p>
<pre>String 1: 4dc968ff0ee35c209572d4777b721587d36fa7b21bdc56b74a3dc0783e7b9518afbfa20<strong style="background: red;">0</strong>a8284bf36e8e4b55b35f427593d849676da0d1<strong style="background: red;">5</strong>55d8360fb5f07fea2
String 2: 4dc968ff0ee35c209572d4777b721587d36fa7b21bdc56b74a3dc0783e7b9518afbfa20<strong style="background: red;">2</strong>a8284bf36e8e4b55b35f427593d849676da0d1<strong style="background: red;">d</strong>55d8360fb5f07fea2
Hash:     008ee33a9d58b51cfeb425b0959121c9</pre>
<p>The next thing step to safe password storage is called salting. Salting is essentially inserting characters in the string before hashing it. “Hello” can become “H1e2l3lo” if you insert “123” after every alternate character. This means that the hashed file is now much more secure because an intruder would have to know the specific salting technique, which is usually based on server timestamp, tokens, or something unguessable.</p>
<p>Now, even though collisions are common in MD5, it’s still much much better at storing sensitive information than plain text. Since intruders usually just match your hashed file to hashes of common passwords, dictionary words, combinations, etc., if you have a nice, long password, the brute force method becomes inefficient.</p>
<p>This is why, as long as passwords are lengthy and therefore relatively secure, “outdated” hashing algorithms such as MD5 are also actually not a bad choice if it&#8217;s as simple as <code>md5($string)</code> vs <code>$string</code> when storing the password.  I have a nice long Facebook password, and I’ve decided to make its MD5 hash public to prove my point:</p>
<pre>cf7dd0b01c061029778c72facdc14451</pre>
<p>Even though it&#8217;s <em>just</em> MD5, I don&#8217;t think anyone can decrypt it. Not for 573 quadrillion years, at least.</p>
<p><strong>Footnote: </strong>I&#8217;m not saying that we should use MD5 to sign TLS certificates, that&#8217;s crazy talk. All I&#8217;m saying is that (a) MD5 is better than plain text, and (b) it works for practical purposes, as long as there&#8217;s no sensitive data to be accessed and the user has a long, non-dictionary password.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tokens for Authentication</title>
		<link>/tokens/</link>
		<pubDate>Mon, 13 Feb 2017 08:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coffee Time]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://accessibility.co.in/websites/anandchowdhary.com/?p=49</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Something that I've started experimenting recently with is token-based authentication. Since I've been using more JavaScript and less PHP, I figured I can try using tokens in a RESTful API instead of sessions on the server. Instead of using a framework like OAuth (which I highly recommend using), I tried to recreate the token process. This is what I came up with.

This is usually how the process works: A user logs in, and a token is generated. The token is stored on the client (usually in a session, lately also as a local storage object). Then, to call an API, the view also sends the token. The server checks the integrity of the token and returns the relevant response. Each token contains a "private key" of sorts that only the server could've created. JWT does this really well. My way includes a hashed username and timestamp.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Something that I&#8217;ve started experimenting recently with is token-based authentication. Since I&#8217;ve been using more JavaScript and less PHP, I figured I can try using tokens in a RESTful API instead of sessions on the server. Instead of using a framework like OAuth (which I highly recommend using), I tried to recreate the token process. Here&#8217;s what I came up with.</p>
<p>This is usually how the process works: A user logs in, and a token is generated. The token is stored on the client (usually in a session, lately also as a local storage object). Then, to call an API, the view also sends the token. The server checks the integrity of the token and returns the relevant response. Each token contains a &#8220;private key&#8221; of sorts that only the server could&#8217;ve created. JWT does this really well. This my how I did it while playing:</p>
<p>A hashed version of the user unique key (a primary key like ID or, like I used, username) along with the date of 2 days into the future. In PHP, I wrote it like this:</p>
<pre>$token = md5($input["username"] . date("Ymd", strtotime("+2 days")) . "secretkey123");</pre>
<p>In this case, the non-hashed string looks like <code>anand20160216secretkeyq123</code>. I use this particular one because it&#8217;s going to be unique for every user (username) and it has a &#8220;secret&#8221; key. I chose +2 days because of how I&#8217;m checking for integrity:</p>
<p>When an API request is sent, the username is sent too, and the server knows the date. So we create two strings, username + date 1 day in the future + &#8220;secret&#8221; key, and another with the date 2 days into the future. So if a user logs in at 11:00 pm, the key works for 25 hours, and if a user logs in at 1:00 am, it works for 47 hours. Either way, a key works for at least one day and at most two days. This is good because we don&#8217;t want the key to work for more than a day or two.</p>
<h2>Why this is bad</h2>
<p>This is bad because we have no way of killing the token if a session is ended. When a user logs out and logs in again at the same, essentially the same key is generated because it&#8217;s dependent only on the server date. It works as a science experiment, but a fully-developed and tested framework like JWT or OAuth works for real-life projects.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>URL Shortener Length</title>
		<link>/url-shortener-length/</link>
		<pubDate>Fri, 25 Nov 2016 09:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Blog]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Coffee Time]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://accessibility.co.in/websites/anandchowdhary.com/?p=53</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[I made a small URL shortener for Oswald at osw.li in an hour using PHP and MySQL, but I want to learn the MEAN stack, so I thought that this could be a fun starter project. One interesting decision was to decide how many characters the shortened URL’s slug be.

There can be 64 possible characters: A to Z, a to z, 0 to 9, – and _. Even if we make a 3-digit slug, there can be 64^3 = 262,144 possible URLs, which is a big number. The trouble happens with collisions, though. After how many URLs would a pseudorandom generator have repetition? I wrote some JavaScript to find out.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>I made a small URL shortener for Oswald at <a href="https://osw.li/">osw.li</a> in an hour using PHP and MySQL, but I want to learn the MEAN stack, so I thought that this could be a fun starter project. One interesting decision was to decide how many characters the shortened URL’s slug be.</p>
<p>There can be 64 possible characters: A to Z, a to z, 0 to 9, – and _. Even if we make a 3-digit slug, there can be 64^3 = 262,144 possible URLs, which is a big number. The trouble happens with collisions, though. After how many URLs would a pseudorandom generator have repetition? I wrote some JavaScript to find out.</p>
<p>It essentially creates slugs until they’re repeated and returns the number at while repetition happened. It does this 10,000 times and logs the average.</p>
<pre>function randomString(length) {
	var result = "", chars = "0123456789abcdefghijklmnopqrstuvwxyzABCDEFGHIJKLMNOPQRSTUVWXYZ_-";
	for (var i = length; i &gt; 0; --i) result += chars[Math.floor(Math.random() * chars.length)];
	return result;
}
for (k = 0; k &lt; 5; k++) {
	var bosarr = [];
	for (j = 0; j &lt; 10000; j++) {
		var arr = [];
		var duplicate = 0;
		do {
			var num = randomString(k);
			var check = 0;
			for (i = 0; i &lt; arr.length; i++) {
				if (arr[i] == num) {
					check++;
				}
			}
			if (check == 0) {
				arr.push(num);
			} else {
				duplicate++;
			}
		} while (duplicate &lt;= 0);
		bosarr.push(arr.length);
	}
	var sum = 0;
	for (i = 0; i &lt; bosarr.length; i++) {
		sum += parseInt(bosarr[i], 10);
	}
	var avg = sum / bosarr.length;
	console.log("For a " + k + "-digit string, there will be repetition after " + avg + " strings");
}
</pre>
<p>For a 3-character slug, repetition happened at around 640. This means that after around 600 shortened URLs, we would have to re-generate a slug. For a 4-character one, it was around 5,000. And for 5, it was around 40,000.</p>
<p>Of course, we’ll also check if the slug exists, but to (mostly) avoid it, a 5-character slug makes most sense. 40,000 URLs before we have to ever re-generate. Interesting.</p>
<section class="entry-content cf"><strong>Footnote:</strong> If the odds are that repetition happens after 40,000 URLs, do we really have to send in a database query every time to check? And if we’re doing that, why not stick to 4-character ones? They’re shorter, and there can be over 16 million possible URLs. I pick 5-character because the probability gets reduced by over 6 times by adding one character, but 4 isn’t too bad if we’re checking anyway.</section>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Naari</title>
		<link>/naari/</link>
		<pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 10:25:47 +0000</pubDate>
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[admin]]></dc:creator>
				<category><![CDATA[Projects]]></category>

		<guid isPermaLink="false">http://accessibility.co.in/websites/anandchowdhary.com/?p=67</guid>
		<description><![CDATA[Naari is the end-to-end period healthcare companion—from giving you personalized tampon recommendations using P&#038;G’s survey data and HPE’s machine learning APIs, to getting those products delivered to your doorstep via Amazon. Naari is also a social platform that lets you chat with your doctor, friends, or anonymously in a group to find someone who has previously experienced what you are experiencing and express yourself freely, and get a daily curated feed of women’s health articles and news from leading journals.]]></description>
				<content:encoded><![CDATA[<p>Naari is the end-to-end period healthcare companion—from giving you personalized tampon recommendations using P&amp;G’s survey data and HPE’s machine learning APIs, to getting those products delivered to your doorstep via Amazon. Naari is also a social platform that lets you chat with your doctor, friends, or anonymously in a group to find someone who has previously experienced what you are experiencing and express yourself freely, and get a daily curated feed of women’s health articles and news from leading journals.</p>
<p>Winner, AngelHack Lady Problems Delhi 2016 · P&amp;G Sponsor Award</p>
<p><a href="http://naariapp.org/" target="_blank">Try Naari</a> · <a href="http://www.hackathon.io/71444" target="_blank">Read the intro</a></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-69" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/a.png" alt="" width="960" height="550" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/a.png 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/a-300x172.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/a-768x440.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></p>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8220;Great use of machine learning to drive a benefit for women.&#8221;</em><br />
<small>&#8212; Erik Hasenoehrl, Research Fellow, Procter &amp; Gamble</small></p></blockquote>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-70" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/b.png" alt="" width="960" height="550" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/b.png 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/b-300x172.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/b-768x440.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-71" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/b2.png" alt="" width="960" height="550" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/b2.png 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/b2-300x172.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/b2-768x440.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></p>
<blockquote><p><em>&#8220;Takes care of both health and cultural aspects [of sexual health.]&#8221;<br />
</em><small>&#8212; Simmi Dhamija, Strategic Initiative &amp; Performance Management Leader, Tech Mahindra</small></p></blockquote>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-72" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/c.png" alt="" width="960" height="550" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/c.png 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/c-300x172.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/c-768x440.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></p>
<p><img class="alignnone size-full wp-image-73" src="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/d.png" alt="" width="960" height="550" srcset="/wp-content/uploads/2017/04/d.png 960w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/d-300x172.png 300w, /wp-content/uploads/2017/04/d-768x440.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /></p>
]]></content:encoded>
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
