<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>New Delhi on Anand Chowdhary</title>
    <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/places/new-delhi/</link>
    <description>Recent content in New Delhi on Anand Chowdhary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://anandchowdhary.com/places/new-delhi/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>BharatHacks</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/bharathacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/bharathacks/</guid>
      <description>I organized BharatHacks, a hackathon for solving India-specific problems. Programmers, designers, engineers, and entrepreneurs came together to build products to make the lives of a billion Indians better. I organized in collaboration with Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Developer Circle Delhi-NCR and delivered the introductory keynote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEDxHaileyRoad</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/tedx-hailey-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/tedx-hailey-road/</guid>
      <description>I gave my first TEDx talk at TEDxHaileyRoad in New Delhi in June 2017 on Designing for Inclusion, where I talked about my story in starting Oswald Labs and rethinking today&amp;rsquo;s approach to ignore accessibility and inclusion in design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tech Charcha by Facebook DevC</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/tech-charcha/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 May 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/tech-charcha/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was part of a panel discussion on the future of technology by Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Developer Circles Delhi-NCR along with Chinmaya Saxena, Developer Programs Lead, Facebook India; Saransh Kataria, Chapter Lead, Facebook Developer Circle Delhi; and Shubhamoy Chakrabarty, COO at Cloudtub, Inc.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIP Launch (DTU)</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/sip-launch-dtu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/sip-launch-dtu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was the keynote speaker at the launch of the Startup Internship Portal of Delhi Technological University (DTU), where I did the first public revealing of Oswald Labs&amp;rsquo; R&amp;amp;D blind-friendly smartphone OS, Shravan and talked about the opportunity of working with startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>coDelhi</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/codelhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/codelhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spoke about education technology and my startup ClassRebels at Co|Delhi, the flagship Android and web development hackathon of Delhi Technological University (DTU). I delivered two talks, one on the first day about edtech and the other about our stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>