<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Artificial Intelligence on Anand Chowdhary</title>
    <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/work/artificial-intelligence/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Artificial Intelligence on Anand Chowdhary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://anandchowdhary.com/work/artificial-intelligence/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Aristotle</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/aristotle/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/aristotle/</guid>
      <description>The product was a progressive web app built using Vue/Nuxt.js powered by Django and Firebase.
The app also included Oswald Labs&amp;rsquo; accessibility features to make it more usable for student with dyslexia, visual impairment, and more disabilities, along with a chatbot to answer students&amp;rsquo; frequently asked questions which could be trained by all teachers.
      The branding and pitch were inspired from CGP Grey&amp;rsquo;s video, Digital Aristotle.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CLShare</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/clshare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/clshare/</guid>
      <description>On a Thursday/Friday in November 2018, my team and I built and presented CLShare, an app to help CLS Group with employee engagement. The app was the winner of the CLS Engagement App Challenge in London and uses a combination of an AI chatbot with employee-to-employee communication to foster engagement.
View GitHub repo &amp;rarr;
    The product was a progressive web app built using Vue/Nuxt.js powered by Firebase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wendy</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/wendy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/wendy/</guid>
      <description>On a weekend in March 2018, I build Wendy, a smartphone-based home security system with real-time face detection and a chatbot interface. Instead of a €200 Nest device, Wendy uses a €30 smartphone mounted as a doorbell.
As soon as someone approaches your door, Wendy checks their face against your trusted contacts and lets you know in case she doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize them. She also checks the entire Netherlands&amp;rsquo; Police database of missing or wanted persons and alerts the authorities in case a match is found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RefuServe</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/refuserve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/refuserve/</guid>
      <description>In November 2017, I worked with Trivago in Düsseldorf on building an app to help refugees find jobs in Europe. RefuServe is a chatbot app that helps you develop your skills by recommending videos and translating them in your native language, along with automatically generating resumes for you in multiple languages. No matter where you&amp;rsquo;re from, RefuServe will help you find a job in Europe.
View GitHub repo &amp;rarr;
        This project was done in collaboration with Mohit Ahuja 🇮🇳.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FaceMatch</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/facematch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/facematch/</guid>
      <description>For the Amazon Web Services (AWS) Hackathon at The Future of High Tech, part of the Startup Fest Europe 2017, I developed FaceMatch, a mobile app that uses deep learning-based facial detection, and displays the results in an augmented reality heads-up display. I ended up winning the hackathon&amp;rsquo;s grand prize of €1,000 along with VIP tickets for StartupFest Europe.
View GitHub repo &amp;rarr;
   The idea is simple — if you enter a large conference or a room full of people, you want to know who you should network with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naari</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/naari/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/naari/</guid>
      <description>Naari (meaning woman in Hindi) is the end-to-end period healthcare companion&amp;mdash;from giving you personalized tampon recommendations using P&amp;amp;G&amp;rsquo;s survey data and HPE&amp;rsquo;s machine learning APIs&amp;mdash;to getting those products delivered to your doorstep via Amazon.
 Great use of machine learning to drive a benefit for women. &amp;ndash; Erik Hasenoehrl, Research Fellow, Procter &amp;amp; Gamble
 Naari is also a social platform that lets you chat with your doctor, friends, or anonymously in a group to find someone who has previously experienced what you are experiencing and express yourself freely, and get a daily curated feed of women&amp;rsquo;s health articles and news from leading journals.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>