<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>App on Anand Chowdhary</title>
    <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/work/app/</link>
    <description>Recent content in App on Anand Chowdhary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://anandchowdhary.com/work/app/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>CLShare</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/clshare/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/clshare/</guid>
      <description>On a Thursday/Friday in November 2018, my team and I built and presented CLShare, an app to help CLS Group with employee engagement. The app was the winner of the CLS Engagement App Challenge in London and uses a combination of an AI chatbot with employee-to-employee communication to foster engagement.
View GitHub repo &amp;rarr;
    The product was a progressive web app built using Vue/Nuxt.js powered by Firebase.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Wendy</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/wendy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/wendy/</guid>
      <description>On a weekend in March 2018, I build Wendy, a smartphone-based home security system with real-time face detection and a chatbot interface. Instead of a €200 Nest device, Wendy uses a €30 smartphone mounted as a doorbell.
As soon as someone approaches your door, Wendy checks their face against your trusted contacts and lets you know in case she doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize them. She also checks the entire Netherlands&amp;rsquo; Police database of missing or wanted persons and alerts the authorities in case a match is found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSUnite</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/csunite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/csunite/</guid>
      <description>I worked with CSU, the Netherlands&amp;rsquo; second-largest cleaning service provider, during the first weekend of March 2018 in the Philips Stadion in Eindhoven as part of their first hackathon, Bright Future Hack. CSUnite is an app for hyperlocal on-demand cleaning services, along with a built-in training and communication platform for employees.
The Progressive Web App was built using Vue.js and Vuetify.js (a material design framework) in 24 hours. It also featured accessibility settings and user ratings, and our pitch included concepts of VR training using Google Cardboard and an Apple Watch app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RefuServe</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/refuserve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/refuserve/</guid>
      <description>In November 2017, I worked with Trivago in Düsseldorf on building an app to help refugees find jobs in Europe. RefuServe is a chatbot app that helps you develop your skills by recommending videos and translating them in your native language, along with automatically generating resumes for you in multiple languages. No matter where you&amp;rsquo;re from, RefuServe will help you find a job in Europe.
View GitHub repo &amp;rarr;
        This project was done in collaboration with Mohit Ahuja 🇮🇳.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capella</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/capella/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/capella/</guid>
      <description>At the Amsterdam Dance Event&amp;rsquo;s hackathon in October 2017, I built Capella in 24 hours, a Progressive Web App that lets you find your friends in concerts using location sharing. You can also make new friends based on similar music taste and discover venue heat-maps.
The app was built using HTML5 with a PHP backend integrated with some machine learning and music tagging APIs. The Spotify-inspired dark UI was also designed, along with a beautiful app icon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FaceMatch</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/facematch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/facematch/</guid>
      <description>For the Amazon Web Services (AWS) Hackathon at The Future of High Tech, part of the Startup Fest Europe 2017, I developed FaceMatch, a mobile app that uses deep learning-based facial detection, and displays the results in an augmented reality heads-up display. I ended up winning the hackathon&amp;rsquo;s grand prize of €1,000 along with VIP tickets for StartupFest Europe.
View GitHub repo &amp;rarr;
   The idea is simple — if you enter a large conference or a room full of people, you want to know who you should network with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naari</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/naari/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/naari/</guid>
      <description>Naari (meaning woman in Hindi) is the end-to-end period healthcare companion&amp;mdash;from giving you personalized tampon recommendations using P&amp;amp;G&amp;rsquo;s survey data and HPE&amp;rsquo;s machine learning APIs&amp;mdash;to getting those products delivered to your doorstep via Amazon.
 Great use of machine learning to drive a benefit for women. &amp;ndash; Erik Hasenoehrl, Research Fellow, Procter &amp;amp; Gamble
 Naari is also a social platform that lets you chat with your doctor, friends, or anonymously in a group to find someone who has previously experienced what you are experiencing and express yourself freely, and get a daily curated feed of women&amp;rsquo;s health articles and news from leading journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi Government</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/delhi-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/delhi-government/</guid>
      <description>In April and May, 2016, I worked with a small team at the Government of Delhi&amp;rsquo;s Directorate of Education to try and streamline the process of communication between state schools and the Directorate. Today, if a school principal has a problem, she has to report a grievance, wait for a response, get redirected to the correct department, find someone, address the problem, and it keeps going on and on. We redesigned this process from group up for efficient, two-way communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeep</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/keeep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/keeep/</guid>
      <description>For my highschool Computer Science project, I built an encryption engine and password manager in C/C++. I wrote a pseudo-encryption algorithm with string manipulation, rotation, and encoding.
Keeep is a lightweight password management and encryption utility for Windows. It stores all usernames, passwords, credit cards, free-form notes, and more, in a securely encrypted file, protected by a single master password. Keeep is written in C++ in Code::Blocks.
Visit GitHub repo &amp;rarr;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baymax</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/baymax/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/baymax/</guid>
      <description>The idea is pretty simple — like in the movie, we need a personal healthcare companion, someone who can help us medically when we need it to, both by providing the right information to us and helping us get in touch with the right medical professionals.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve stubbed your toe a little, Baymax will tell you how to make the swelling go away and will help you get well by providing a treatment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SixteenInches</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/sixteeninches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/sixteeninches/</guid>
      <description>SixteenInches.com is one of the fastest-growing online supplements store. It was built on a foundation of authenticity and quality-control, both of which currently lack the healthcare industry. I was hired to design the SixteenInches&amp;rsquo; brand identity, including logo and social media design, and a responsive ecommerce website on the WordPress platform using Woocommerce, to convey their mission.
I chose red as the primary brand color because it represents power and passion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saga Music</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/saga-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/saga-music/</guid>
      <description>Music has always been an integral part of our lives. Ever since people started using the internet, they&amp;rsquo;ve been downloading music and movies. The process became relatively simple with the introduction of Napster in 1999, which led to the development of many such tools. I remember growing up with Limewire and Bearshare. After the discontinuation of these services in after ten long years, downloading music became really complicated again.
In the 2010s, people stream music on YouTube or Spotify or SoundCloud and use conversion tools to download MP3 files, or use services such as BeeMP3 or MP3Skull which are full of advertisements, fake links, and incomplete collections.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>