<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Enschede on Anand Chowdhary</title>
    <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/places/enschede/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Enschede on Anand Chowdhary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://anandchowdhary.com/places/enschede/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>SpeakUp</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/speakup/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/speakup/</guid>
      <description>In September 2018, SpeakUp, an Enschede-based VoIP and cloud telephony company, celebrated its 15th birthday. At the Speakup Partner &amp;amp; Jubileum Event, I was one of the presenters to showcase their upcoming projects into spaces like AI and mobile.
Photos © Masterphoto/SpeakUp
      </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NESST Season 3</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/nesst-season-3/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/nesst-season-3/</guid>
      <description>New Entrepreneurial Student Society Twente (NESST) is a not-for-profit early-stage startup accelerator in Enschede. After being a speaker, advisor, and Dragons&amp;rsquo; Den judge at their third season, I was invited as the keynote speaker for the first day of Season 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>GOGBOT</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/gogbot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/gogbot/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;GOGBOT is an annual art, technology, and music festival in Enschede. In 2011, the festival was awarded the National Innovation Award, being the most innovative festival in the Netherlands. In 2018, my team and I were featured in the festival.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Online Open Day</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/online-open-day/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/online-open-day/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At the University of Twente&amp;rsquo;s first annual Online Open Day, I spoke about startups, entrepreneurship, and technology at the university, as part of a panel called &amp;ldquo;Beyond Your Studies,&amp;rdquo; moderated by co-founder and project manager of DesignLab, Miriam Iliohan.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NESST Season 2</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/nesst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/nesst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After being featured by Het Financieele Dagblad (Dutch Financial Times) as one of the Netherlands&amp;rsquo; 50 most-innovative young entrepreneurs and professionals, I was invited by Enschede-based non-profit startup accelerator NESST to deliver the opening keynote for their new season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Startup24</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/startup24/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 11 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/startup24/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Startup24 is the flagship startup weekend-like event in the Netherlands which happens in 12 cities simultaneously. I was invited to Startup24 Enschede to do a pitching working for the participants before their final jury pitches, and I was also part of their &amp;ldquo;midnight jury&amp;rdquo; for 2-minute pitches at midnight.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Hardstart Pitch Training</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/hardstart-pitch-training/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/hardstart-pitch-training/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I developed and conducted a startup pitching workshop for student entrepreneurship organization and incubator Hardstart&amp;rsquo;s flagship pitching event, &lt;em&gt;Pitch that Bitch&lt;/em&gt;. It was the first time that I conducted a workshop for fellow student entrepreneurs, and it was definitely a very interesting experience.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>