<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Anand Chowdhary</title>
    <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Anand Chowdhary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM IoT Escape Room</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/ibm-iot-escape-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/ibm-iot-escape-room/</guid>
      <description>From February to April 2018, my project group and I worked with IBM on building an escape room using—and to teach players about—the Internet of Things. Using Wemoses and Ardiuos as the basic building blocks, combined with Firebase&amp;rsquo;s real-time database and a custom-built Vue.js app, we built a proof-of-concept with five connected puzzles.
This was my project for the module &amp;ldquo;Living and Working Tomorrow&amp;rdquo;, a quarter of Creative Technology BSc&amp;rsquo;s first year focused on working with external clients on solving today&amp;rsquo;s problems using tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CSUnite</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/csunite/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/csunite/</guid>
      <description>I worked with CSU, the Netherlands&amp;rsquo; second-largest cleaning service provider, during the first weekend of March 2018 in the Philips Stadion in Eindhoven as part of their first hackathon, Bright Future Hack. CSUnite is an app for hyperlocal on-demand cleaning services, along with a built-in training and communication platform for employees.
The Progressive Web App was built using Vue.js and Vuetify.js (a material design framework) in 24 hours. It also featured accessibility settings and user ratings, and our pitch included concepts of VR training using Google Cardboard and an Apple Watch app.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>DrillMaps</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/drillmaps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/drillmaps/</guid>
      <description>In February and March 2018, I worked with DrillMaps, a horizontal directional drilling startup based in Seattle, WA. I designed and developed their new website, along with coherent icons for their products.
The website was built using Vue.js and included Firebase&amp;rsquo;s authentication and real-time database for mapping and visualization. It also integrated with Chargebee and Stripe for billing and subscriptions.
Visit DrillMaps &amp;rarr;
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueboard</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/blueboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/blueboard/</guid>
      <description>BlueBoard is a Bluetooth-powered smart billboard that actually cares about you. Privacy-first and context-aware, it connects with your smartphone via Bluetooth and shows you relevant advertisements and information.
Users can open the BlueBoard app and set their preferences by assigning points from 0 to 10 to everything you they like — from technology and fashion to food and the weather. BlueBoard listens to the app and securely transfers their preference data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>RefuServe</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/refuserve/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/refuserve/</guid>
      <description>In November 2017, I worked with Trivago in Düsseldorf on building an app to help refugees find jobs in Europe. RefuServe is a chatbot app that helps you develop your skills by recommending videos and translating them in your native language, along with automatically generating resumes for you in multiple languages. No matter where you&amp;rsquo;re from, RefuServe will help you find a job in Europe.
View GitHub repo &amp;rarr;
        This project was done in collaboration with Mohit Ahuja 🇮🇳.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Capella</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/capella/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Oct 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/capella/</guid>
      <description>At the Amsterdam Dance Event (ADE)&amp;rsquo;s hackathon in October 2017, I built Capella in 24 hours, a Progressive Web App that lets you find your friends in concerts using location sharing. You can also make new friends based on similar music taste and discover venue heat-maps.
The app was built using HTML5 with a PHP backend integrated with some machine learning and music tagging APIs. The Spotify-inspired dark UI was also developed, along with a beautiful app icon.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FaceMatch</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/facematch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 23 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/facematch/</guid>
      <description>For the Amazon Web Services (AWS) Hackathon at The Future of High Tech, part of the Startup Fest Europe 2017, I developed FaceMatch, a mobile app that uses deep learning-based facial detection, and displays the results in an augmented reality heads-up display. I ended up winning the hackathon&amp;rsquo;s grand prize of €1,000 along with VIP tickets for StartupFest Europe.
View GitHub repo &amp;rarr;
   The idea is simple — if you enter a large conference or a room full of people, you want to know who you should network with.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Crink Jewel</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/crinkjewel/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Sep 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/crinkjewel/</guid>
      <description>I designed a minimal logo and Shopify ecommerce store for Crink Jewel, a precious jewelry company based in New Delhi, India. I tried to portray elegance, simplicity, and timelessness.
          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BharatHacks</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/bharathacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/bharathacks/</guid>
      <description>In June 2017, I organized BharatHacks, a hackathon for solving India-specific problems. Programmers, designers, engineers, and entrepreneurs came together to build products to make lives better. Organized in collaboration with Facebook Developer Circle Delhi-NCR, BharatHacks helped hundreds take their idea forward, from hacking to raising investment and launching their products in the market.
BharatHacks was free for both entrepreneurs and hackers, to join hands and work towards a better India. From a pool of over 1,000 applicants, we&amp;rsquo;ve chosen the top 200 to participate at BharatHacks.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Melangebox</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/melangebox/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 01 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/melangebox/</guid>
      <description>In early 2017, Mahendra Singh Raghuwanshi and I co-founded Melangebox, a fashion ecommerce startup. I designed the brand identity and developed a mobile-first Shopify store, and Mahendra handled the production, inventory, and shipping. In mid-2018, we had grown to over ₹50,000 ($750) in revenue every day and continue to grow.
Visit Melangebox &amp;rarr;
 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Naari</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/naari/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Oct 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/naari/</guid>
      <description>Naari (meaning woman in Hindi) is the end-to-end period healthcare companion&amp;mdash;from giving you personalized tampon recommendations using P&amp;amp;G&amp;rsquo;s survey data and HPE&amp;rsquo;s machine learning APIs&amp;mdash;to getting those products delivered to your doorstep via Amazon.
 Great use of machine learning to drive a benefit for women. &amp;ndash; Erik Hasenoehrl, Research Fellow, Procter &amp;amp; Gamble
 Naari is also a social platform that lets you chat with your doctor, friends, or anonymously in a group to find someone who has previously experienced what you are experiencing and express yourself freely, and get a daily curated feed of women&amp;rsquo;s health articles and news from leading journals.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Delhi Government</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/delhi-government/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/delhi-government/</guid>
      <description>In April and May, 2016, I worked with a small team at the Government of Delhi&amp;rsquo;s Directorate of Education to try and streamline the process of communication between state schools and the Directorate. Today, if a school principal has a problem, she has to report a grievance, wait for a response, get redirected to the correct department, find someone, address the problem, and it keeps going on and on. We redesigned this process from group up for efficient, two-way communication.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Firangana</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/firangana/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Mar 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/firangana/</guid>
      <description>In mid-2016, my girlfriend Sukriti Kapoor and I conceptualized a fashion brand that combines western clothing with ethnic Indian designs. She worked on fabric and fashion design while I designed the brand identity and website.
          </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Keeep</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/keeep/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Jan 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/keeep/</guid>
      <description>For my highschool Computer Science project, I built an encryption engine and password manager in C/C++.
Visit GitHub repo &amp;rarr;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Baymax</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/baymax/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Dec 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/baymax/</guid>
      <description>The idea is pretty simple — like in the movie, we need a personal healthcare companion, someone who can help us medically when we need it to, both by providing the right information to us and helping us get in touch with the right medical professionals.
If you&amp;rsquo;ve stubbed your toe a little, Baymax will tell you how to make the swelling go away and will help you get well by providing a treatment.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SixteenInches</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/sixteeninches/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 12 Sep 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/sixteeninches/</guid>
      <description>SixteenInches.com is one of the fastest-growing online supplements store. It was built on a foundation of authenticity and quality-control, both of which currently lack the healthcare industry. I was hired to design the SixteenInches&amp;rsquo; brand identity, including logo and social media design, and a responsive ecommerce website on the WordPress platform using Woocommerce, to convey their mission.
I chose red as the primary brand color because it represents power and passion.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Saga Music</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/saga-music/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 31 May 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/saga-music/</guid>
      <description>Music has always been an integral part of our lives. Ever since people started using the internet, they&amp;rsquo;ve been downloading music and movies. The process became relatively simple with the introduction of Napster in 1999, which led to the development of many such tools. I remember growing up with Limewire and Bearshare. After the discontinuation of these services in after ten long years, downloading music became really complicated again.
In the 2010s, people stream music on YouTube or Spotify or SoundCloud and use conversion tools to download MP3 files, or use services such as BeeMP3 or MP3Skull which are full of advertisements, fake links, and incomplete collections.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Justice Adda</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/justice-adda/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/justice-adda/</guid>
      <description>From late 2014 to early 2016, I worked as the Technology Lead at Justice Adda, a startup part of Cambridge Social Ventures in the Judge Business School, University of Cambridge. I designed their early website and webapps like Intolerance Tracker. I also worked on their branding, and this is a small Paul Rand-inspired magazine I designed to showcase the new brand.
                            </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project Blue</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/project-blue/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Jul 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/project-blue/</guid>
      <description>Project Blue, originally standing for &amp;lsquo;Bottles, Linkages, and their Underlining Ergonomics,&amp;rsquo; is my first (and only) industrial design project in which I conducted a research and redesigned the plastic bottle. I understood that polyethene terephthalate, a plastic resin and the most common type of polyester, is the material which makes the popular &amp;lsquo;PET&amp;rsquo; bottles.
According to the National Association for PET Container Resources (NAPCOR), the gross water bottle recycling rate was only 38.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Cyankart</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/cyankart/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 21 Jun 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/cyankart/</guid>
      <description>Cyankart.com is India&amp;rsquo;s most popular online fashion store for phone cases and apparel items. They were looking to expand their mobile reach and increase conversions, so I was hired to redesign their ecommerce website and provide logistics-related backend solutions. A/B testing, source code minification, image optimization, and responsive cross-platform mobile-first Liquid theme development are just some of the complicated words I used while working with Cyankart to expand their mobile reach and increase conversions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Unifiers</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/unifiers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 May 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/unifiers/</guid>
      <description>ClassRebels is a Bluetooth-powered smart billboard that actually cares about you. Privacy-first and context-aware, it connects with your smartphone via Bluetooth and shows you relevant advertisements and information.
Users can open the ClassRebels app and set their preferences by assigning points from 0 to 10 to everything you they like — from technology and fashion to food and the weather. ClassRebels listens to the app and securely transfers their preference data.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Made with Love in India</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/made-with-love-in-india/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 21 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/made-with-love-in-india/</guid>
      <description>You see this meticulously made handicraft item which would be the perfect addition to brighten up any living room. You pick it up, admiring the attention to detail when suddenly you spot the Made in India label at the bottom, instantly making the product you were admiring seconds ago feel as cheap as dirt.
Why is it that a Made in Italy label makes people feel as if the product had been made in heaven itself?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>ClassRebels</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/classrebels/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/classrebels/</guid>
      <description>Unlike all stories, ClassRebels didn&amp;rsquo;t start with the simple idea of making teachers and students connect in a way they&amp;rsquo;ve never connected before. It started with an idea to bring about a reform, a change, and a revolution. In India, this change was long needed. The society is evolving, and our education system needs to catch up.
We believe that the whole idea of education is taken in the wrong sense.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Internet.org</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/internet.org/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/internet.org/</guid>
      <description>I recently participated in an event where I was required to redesign Internet.org&amp;rsquo;s homepage and logo. The content had to remain the same, but the design was to be completely new. The website was required to be responsive, and good in code-quality and aesthetics, without the use of any external code. The logo was marked for creativity and execution. Here&amp;rsquo;s what I designed in five hours. And why.
Read the article on Medium &amp;rarr;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>