<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Internet of Things on Anand Chowdhary</title>
    <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/work/internet-of-things/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Internet of Things on Anand Chowdhary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://anandchowdhary.com/work/internet-of-things/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Wendy</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/wendy/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 May 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/wendy/</guid>
      <description>On a weekend in March 2018, I build Wendy, a smartphone-based home security system with real-time face detection and a chatbot interface. Instead of a €200 Nest device, Wendy uses a €30 smartphone mounted as a doorbell.
As soon as someone approaches your door, Wendy checks their face against your trusted contacts and lets you know in case she doesn&amp;rsquo;t recognize them. She also checks the entire Netherlands&amp;rsquo; Police database of missing or wanted persons and alerts the authorities in case a match is found.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>IBM IoT Escape Room</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/ibm-iot-escape-room/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Apr 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/ibm-iot-escape-room/</guid>
      <description>From February to April 2018, my project group and I worked with IBM on building an escape room using—and to teach players about—the Internet of Things. Using Wemoses and Ardiuos as the basic building blocks, combined with Firebase&amp;rsquo;s real-time database and a custom-built Vue.js app, we built a proof-of-concept with five connected puzzles.
This was my project for the module &amp;ldquo;Living and Working Tomorrow&amp;rdquo;, a quarter of Creative Technology BSc&amp;rsquo;s first year focused on working with external clients on solving today&amp;rsquo;s problems using tomorrow&amp;rsquo;s technology.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Blueboard</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/blueboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jan 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/projects/blueboard/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;BlueBoard is a Bluetooth-powered smart billboard that actually cares about you. Privacy-first and context-aware, it connects with your smartphone via Bluetooth and shows you relevant advertisements and information.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>