<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Speaker on Anand Chowdhary</title>
    <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/roles/speaker/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Speaker on Anand Chowdhary</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://anandchowdhary.com/roles/speaker/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>NESST Season 3</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/nesst-season-4/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Sep 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/nesst-season-4/</guid>
      <description>New Entrepreneurial Student Society Twente (NESST) is a not-for-profit early-stage startup accelerator in Enschede. After being a speaker, advisor, and Dragons&amp;rsquo; Den judge at their third season, I was invited as the keynote speaker for the first day of Season 4.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>eSummit</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/esummit/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/esummit/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;At IIT Kanpur&amp;rsquo;s flagship entrepreneurship event, eSummit 2018, I was invited to speak about my journey, lessons, and upcoming opportunities in technology. I was part of the Forbes 30 Under 30 session which featured entrepreneurs from this year&amp;rsquo;s list sharing their experiences before a Q&amp;amp;A session.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>HackIIITD</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/hackiiitd/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/hackiiitd/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As our first-ever sponsored event, I was a speaker, mentor, and judge at IIIT Delhi&amp;rsquo;s flagship hackathon, HackIIITD. Oswald Labs sponsored the winning prize (a spot in our accelerator program) along with a cash prize. We saw some exciting ideas — everything from 2FA and key management for blockchain to autonomous drones for military applications to meme video generators.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>MINET X 2018</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/minet-x-2018/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/minet-x-2018/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I went back to my alma mater, The Mother&amp;rsquo;s International School, as the keynote speaker for their annual technology and entrepreneurship event, X, organized by the computer club MINET. I spoke about my journey from a highschool student to today, and the lessons that came with it. The talk was a modified version of the NESST keynote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>NESST Season 2</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/nesst/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Mar 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/nesst/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;After being featured by Het Financieele Dagblad (Dutch Financial Times) as one of the Netherlands&amp;rsquo; 50 most-innovative young entrepreneurs and professionals, I was invited by Enschede-based non-profit startup accelerator NESST to deliver the opening keynote for their new season.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>BharatHacks</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/bharathacks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/bharathacks/</guid>
      <description>I organized BharatHacks, a hackathon for solving India-specific problems. Programmers, designers, engineers, and entrepreneurs came together to build products to make the lives of a billion Indians better. I organized in collaboration with Facebook&amp;rsquo;s Developer Circle Delhi-NCR and delivered the introductory keynote.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>TEDxHaileyRoad</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/tedx-hailey-road/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 17 Jun 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/tedx-hailey-road/</guid>
      <description>I gave my first TEDx talk at TEDxHaileyRoad in New Delhi in June 2017 on Designing for Inclusion, where I talked about my story in starting Oswald Labs and rethinking today&amp;rsquo;s approach to ignore accessibility and inclusion in design.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>SIP Launch (DTU)</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/sip-launch-dtu/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/sip-launch-dtu/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I was the keynote speaker at the launch of the Startup Internship Portal of Delhi Technological University (DTU), where I did the first public revealing of Oswald Labs&amp;rsquo; R&amp;amp;D blind-friendly smartphone OS, Shravan and talked about the opportunity of working with startups.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>coDelhi</title>
      <link>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/codelhi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Mar 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://anandchowdhary.com/events/codelhi/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;I spoke about education technology and my startup ClassRebels at Co|Delhi, the flagship Android and web development hackathon of Delhi Technological University (DTU). I delivered two talks, one on the first day about edtech and the other about our stack.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>